nextscripts.com 2013-11-11

# Privacy Policy - NextScriptsNextScripts

PRIVACY STATEMENT

NextScripts.com gathers information for the primary reason of enhancing our customers experience on our website. This privacy policy is intended to act as a guide to consumers to explain what information we are gathering about them when they visit our website. Here you will find an outline of how we intend use information, and what methods we have in place to protect your privacy. 

This Privacy Statement applies only to the information gathered online at NextScripts.com and not to any third party or affiliate sites that you find links to on our site. 

INFORMATION GATHERED ON OUR WEBSITE

1\. General Browsing Information 

NextScripts.com collects information during all visits to our website. While we are gathering this information, personal and non-personal (such as domain type, browser/version, ISP, and your IP address) will be added to our database. This information allows NextScripts.com to determine how our website is used by you, including which pages are most frequently visited or when these pages were last accessed. This information also helps us determine any technical issues our website has and improve the services we offer (such as the determination of how much time it takes a visitor to connect to our site or to download a page). Navigation information helps us understand your use of NextScripts.com and allows us the chance to improve your experience by adding extra features, services or products. 

2\. Personal Information

NextScripts.com requests personal information when you set up or revise a NextScripts.com account, sign up for NextScripts.com e-mail, shop online, check the status of your orders, You may also make decisions to sign up to receive information about improved products, promotions or services via email or other communication methods.

Information includes name, physical/mailing address, e-mail address, recipient’s name and e-mail address, order information, telephone numbers, credit or debit card numbers, and messages or reminders. You may opt in or out of this information collection.

We further gather information from you when you visit us from other websites that may allow you the opportunity to register for NextScripts.com e-mail. Information collected includes name, home mailing address and e-mail address.

HOW WE USE THE PERSONAL INFORMATION GATHERED HERE

NextScripts.com is allowed to use personal information collected to help deliver products, contact you when necessary, or contact gift recipient(s). These would not be done unless we had questions or required additional information or orders for delivery purposes. Information will also be used for validation purposes, respond to questions on our website or to help deliver services and/or information about products, promotions or the website, including entering your name in theNextScripts.com e-mail listings or other mailing lists or if you place an order.

All information provided will be used when you visit us from third party or affiliate sites to sign up forNextScripts.com e-mail and to send updates aboutNextScripts.com, including promotions and events. In addition, name and mailing address may be used in all the ways outlined in this privacy statement and your e-mail address could be used as designated in this privacy statement.

NextScripts.com E-MAIL 

NextScripts.com e-mail allows exclusive access to special offers, events, new products and more. You may register by completing a sign up form requesting these messages. If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from future delivery of NextScripts.com e-mail, follow the removal instructions located at the bottom of each message or complete the unsubscribe from e-mail form on our site. Removal from NextScripts.com e-mail may not prevent you from receiving all e-mail communications such as those that concern orders placed at NextScripts.com or requests to participate in product surveys. 

INFORMATION SHARED WITH THIRD PARTIES 

We often use third parties to allow us to provide additional services including order fulfillment, payment processing, site activity, administration of e-mail communications. Often these third parties supply information on the performance of our site to us and/or other groups we designate.

If you place an order through NextScripts.com, any personal information provided (such as name, address or credit/debit card information) will be added to our permanent database. We will supply names and/or addresses to companies who have elected to partner with NextScripts.com. Opting out of sharing information with third parties (other than direct service providers) is done by your request in writing. You may also opt out of being added to our mailing list, and your name and mailing address, including purchase information, will not be available to other companies, unless otherwise specified by you, the customer. 

NextScripts.com is also not responsible for the privacy policies of these company sponsoring programs and we encourage you to review the privacy policy those websites.

We may release specific information about you when legally required to do so or when based on our information, we deem it is necessary to be consistent with the law, or it is necessary for the protection of any of our website users or the public.

INFORMATION FOR INTERNATIONAL VISITORS 

Visitors who visit the NextScripts.com website from international locations accept that all orders placed through NextScripts.com are accepted, processed, and shipped from the United States. All information you provide will be preserved in our servers and/or the internal systems which are located in the United States, and may be used and are protected as explained in this privacy policy. 

USE OF COOKIES

1\. Definition of cookies and their use on NextScripts.com

NextScripts.com uses the browser features known as cookies. These a files stored by your web browsers on your computer. Cookies may be used to help track mouse clicks and pass information from your computer to the website when you visit NextScripts.com. Cookies help make our site helpful by providing you with a personalized experience. NextScripts.com uses cookies to track items put in your shopping bag and retains this information for future visits. Cookies also give us the ability to relate navigation information from browsing visits with the personal information you have already provided.

We also use a technology known as clear gifs, which are usually stored in e-mails, which helps us confirming the receipt of our e-mails and provides you with a more personalized experience on our website. 

2\. Shared Cookie Information 

Browsing data gathered by cookies will be shared with others. No personal information gathered by cookies will be shared.

3\. Third-Party Cookie Placement

Third party advertising companies may gather non-personal information by the placement of cookies when you visit their site or when you visit NextScripts.com. These third party sites use the non-personal information including your buying decisions and observe your visits to our website and those to other websites in to create their advertisements aboutNextScripts.com’s products or services. Select companies will give this information to us for evaluating the effectiveness of advertisements they have placed about our products and services and for marketing purposes only. You may opt out of this participation. 

UPDATING PERSONAL INFORMATION 

To help you keep your personal information accurate and up-to-date at all times we offer opportunity to revise or edit your personal information, including billing and shipping information and preferences simply by logging into the “My Account” section of our website.

HOW WE PROTECT CHILDREN ON OUR WEBSITE 

NextScripts.com takes the internet protection of children very seriously. Accordingly, we are in full compliance with federal law. NextScripts.com does not knowingly gather or keep any information provided by anyone under the age of 13.

USE OF LINKS TO OTHER SITES/SERVICES 

Our website contains links to other websites. Third party and affiliate links, provided by NextScripts.com, offer no endorsement nor are we necessarily affiliated with those web sites. NextScripts.com will not be responsible for the privacy practices or content of such web sites. We strongly advise you to examine their privacy policies.

LOCATION OF PRIVACY STATEMENT UPDATES 

Changes made to this privacy policy will be shown within this privacy policy. For the first 30 days, any changes made by NextScripts.com or l changes in how we use information – deletions will be shown as strikeouts and additions will be underlined. Visit often for updates of our privacy policy if at any time you become concerned about personal information and how we are using it or for other announcements from NextScripts.com.

ANSWERING QUESTIONS OR CONCERNS 

We will address any questions or concerns regarding our Privacy Policy, so feel free to contact us as soon as questions or concerns are raised. 

SECURITY STATEMENT

Our security includes limited access data-centers, specific firewall technology, secure socket layer certificate authentication and limited access to our systems. We will never ask you to provide credit card numbers via e-mail. 

NextScripts.com was designed to accept orders only from browsers that allow Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology including (but not limited to) Netscape Navigator 4.0 versions or higher, Internet Explorer versions 7 or higher, Firefox versions 4 or higher and Safari versions 4 or higher. SSL encryption technology secures information you transmit over the Internet. Be advised that 100% security is not always feasible.
